A Guide to the Secretary of Natural Resources Correspondance and Subject Files, 1990-1998
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Secretary of Natural Resources Correspondance and Subject Files, 1990-1998
The Library of Virginia
34693, 35874
8 cu. ft. (8 boxes)
Office of Secretary of Natural Resources
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Accession 34693, transferred and accesioned on 14 July 2004; Accession 35874, transferred and accessioned on 22 June 1998.
Biographical Information
In 1970, the Governor's Management Commission Study recommended the creation of six "Deputy Governors" to assist the Chief Executive in his managerial duties. Compatible functions of government were grouped under these administrative heads, who would serve as the Governor's top management team. The Office of Secretary of Commerce and Resources was created on April 8, 1972. The Secretary of Commerce and Resources was responsible for assisting the Governor in implementing policies for the conservation and use of natural resources, for promoting economic development, providing managerial guidance and direction to Commerce and Resources agencies, and developing and promoting Commerce and Resources programs and budgets. In 1984 the Secretariat was split into two separate offices, the Secretary of Economic Development and the Secretary of Natural Resources.
The Secretary of Natural Resources is a member of the Governor's Cabinet, and is appointed by the governor, and is subject to confirmation by the General Assembly. The Secretary of Natural Resources was responsible for the direction of, or had jurisdiction over, the following state agencies and boards: Chesapeake Bay Local Assistance Department (which became a division of the Department of Conservation and Recreation on July 1, 2004), Department of Conservation and Recreation, Department of Environmental Quality, Department of Game and Inland Fisheries, Department of Historic Resources, Marine Resources Commission, Museum of Natural History, Chippokes Plantation Farm Foundation, and the Virginia Council on Indians. The Secretary of Natural Resources also served as the chairman of the Virginia Land Conservation Foundation, and was a Board Member of the Chesapeake Bay Commission. Additionally, the Secretary of Natural Resources was responsible for many smaller boards and commissions related to water control, pollution, rivers, waste management, and other environmental and recreational issues.
Scope and Content
The Secretary of Natural Resources correspondence and subject files are organized by department and chronologically thereunder. These files consist of correspondence sent between the Secretary of Natural Resources, agency heads, and the general public from 1990 until 1998.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. Correspondence and Subject Files
Contents List
- Series I. Correspondence and Subject Files, 1990-1998., Extent: 8 cu. ft. (8 boxes). (Box 1-8)
  alphabetical, thereunder chronological
  - Accession 34693, 1990-1993.
    This accession is arranged in chronological order.
    - Air Pollution Control, 1992. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Appointments to Boards, Commissions, 1993. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - April, 1990. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - August, 1993. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Avtex, 1988-1989. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Avtex, 1990-1992. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - February, 1990. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Cabinet--Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1990-1993. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - C and R--Eastern Shore State Park, 1991-1992. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Cheatham Annex, 1989-1990. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Chesapeake Bay Local Assistance, 1992. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Congressional Delegation--Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1993. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Conservation and Recreation, 1992. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence from Governor's Office, 1990-1993. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Council on the Environment, 1992. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - DAPC--Botetourt Ordinance, 1992. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - DCR--Bond, Parks and Natural Areas, 1992. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - December, 1993. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Game and Inland Fisheries, 1992. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Historic Resources, 1992. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - January, 1990. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - January, 1994. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - July, 1990. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - June, 1990. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Kim-Stan Landfill, 1991. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Letters Signed by Governor, 1992. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - March, 1990. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Marine Resources Commission, 1992. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - May, 1990. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Medical Waste Management, 1992. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous, 1992. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Natural History Museum, 1992. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - November, 1993. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - October, 1993. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Paid Bills, Travel Reimbursement Requests, etc., July 1992-July 1993. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Resumes and Recommendations, July 1, 1988. (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Secretary Correspondence, 1990-1993. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - September, 1993. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - SJR 104 Study--Clean Air Act LEV/I and M, 1992-1993. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Virginia Legislators--Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1992. (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Waste Management, 1992. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Water Control Board, 1992. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Water Control Board, July 1, 1992. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Accession 35874, 1994-1998.
    - Chesapeake Bay Local Assistance Dept., 1994-1997. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Chesapeake Bay Programs, 1994. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Chesapeake Bay Programs, 1995. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Chesapeake Bay Programs, 1996-1997. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Chesapeake Bay Programs, 1997. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Dept. of Conservation and Recreation, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Dept. of Conservation and Recreation, 1995. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Dept. of Conservation and Recreation, 1995. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Dept. of Conservation and Recreation, 1996. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Dept. of Conservation and Recreation, 1997-1998. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Dept. of Environmental Quality--Air, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Dept. of Environmental Quality--Air, 1995. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Dept. of Environmental Quality--Air, 1996. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Dept. of Environmental Quality--Air, 1997-1998. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Dept. of Environmental Quality--General Correspondence, 1994-1995. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Dept. of Environmental Quality--General Correspondence, 1996-198. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Dept. of Environmental Quality--Waste Management, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Dept. of Environmental Quality--Waste Management, 1995. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Dept. of Environmental Quality--Waste Management, 1996. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Dept. of Environmental Quality--Waste Management, 1997. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Dept. of Environmental Quality--Water, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Dept. of Environmental Quality--Water, 1995. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Dept. of Environmental Quality--Water, 1996. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Dept. of Environmental Quality--Water, 1997. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Dept. of Environmental Quality--Water Records, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Dept. of Game and Inland Fisheries, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Dept. of Game and Inland Fisheries, 1995. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Dept. of Game and Inland Fisheries, 1996. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Dept. of Game and Inland Fisheries, 1997. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Dept. of Historic Resources, 1994-1997. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Marine Resources Commission, 1994-1997. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Secretary Dunlop's Correspondence to Agency Heads, 1994-1997. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Secretary Dunlop's Correspondence to the Governor, 1994-1997. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Museum of Natural History, 1994-1997. (Box 2, Folder 3)